<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Xing Lin</title>
    <link>http://www.cs.utah.edu/~xinglin/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Xing Lin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.cs.utah.edu/~xinglin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Great Papers</title>
      <link>http://www.cs.utah.edu/~xinglin/blog/great-papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.cs.utah.edu/~xinglin/blog/great-papers/</guid>
      <description>There are some papers that are so well written that I really enjoyed reading them. Here is a list of them.
 BlueCache: A Scalable Distributed Flash-based Key-value Store
The system design is very clear from the paper. Learned a lot about its index and data store part.
 What&amp;rsquo;s Really New with NewSQL?
Provides a historial view of how we enter into NewSQL and did an excellent survey of state-of-art NewSQL Databases</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NV-Tree: Reducing Consistency Cost for NVM-based Single Level Systems</title>
      <link>http://www.cs.utah.edu/~xinglin/blog/nv-tree-reducing-consistency-cost-for-nvm-based-single-level-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.cs.utah.edu/~xinglin/blog/nv-tree-reducing-consistency-cost-for-nvm-based-single-level-systems/</guid>
      <description>This paper introduces a new B+ tree variation that is optimized for NVM by reducing consistency cost from memory fence and cacheline flush operations.
 Consistency is guaranteed only for leaf nodes. Internal nodes are re-built from leaf nodes. Elements in leaf nodes are not sorted. A log-structure is used for leaf nodes to remove the need for frequent synchronization. Only appends are added to a leaf node. This also increases concurrency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://www.cs.utah.edu/~xinglin/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.cs.utah.edu/~xinglin/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Xing Lin. I successfully defended my PhD dissertation on July 22nd, 2015! Currently, I am working in the Advanced Technology Group at NetApp.
I was PHD student in the school of computing at the University of Utah. My advisor is Prof. Robert Ricci. I work as a research assistant in the FLUX research group. Before that, I got my Bachelor degree from College of Software, Nankai University, China in 2009.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>http://www.cs.utah.edu/~xinglin/publications/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 20:29:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.cs.utah.edu/~xinglin/publications/publications/</guid>
      <description>PhD Dissertation Using Similarity in Content and Access Patterns to Improve Space Efficiency and Performance in Storage Systems (slides)
Peer-reviewed Papers Storage  Metadata Considered Harmful &amp;hellip; to Deduplication (slides)
Xing Lin, Fred Douglis, Jim Li, Xudong Li, Robert Ricci, Stephen Smaldone, and Grant Wallace
HotStorage 15: 7th USENIX Workshop on Hot Topics in Storage and File Systems, July 2015
 Using Deduplicating Storage for Efficient Disk Image Deployment (slides)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflection After Dissertation Defense</title>
      <link>http://www.cs.utah.edu/~xinglin/blog/reflection-after-dissertation-defense/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.cs.utah.edu/~xinglin/blog/reflection-after-dissertation-defense/</guid>
      <description>After six years in the PhD program, since August 2009, I finally defended my dissertation today. I feel grateful that I finally make it. I do think I am one of the luck ones: I have a really nice adviser and he gives me strong support to do research in areas which I am interested in. I feel grateful for all the help I have received from my advisor, committee members, office mates and co-workers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sketch Data Structures</title>
      <link>http://www.cs.utah.edu/~xinglin/blog/sketch-data-structures/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.cs.utah.edu/~xinglin/blog/sketch-data-structures/</guid>
      <description>Tonight, I went to attend a local meetup event. The talk was given by a faculty from my own department, Jeff Phillips, an assistant professor working in the area of big data analysis. The topic of his talk is about sketch data structure - data structures which uses a much smaller amount of memory to summarize the represented data.This is a cool technique and I am very interested to learn more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KVM Notes</title>
      <link>http://www.cs.utah.edu/~xinglin/blog/kvm-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.cs.utah.edu/~xinglin/blog/kvm-notes/</guid>
      <description>List storage pools
virsh pool-list --details
 List all volumes for a pool
vol-list --details POOLNAME
 To create a Qemu guest with a image in qcow2 format, we need to first create a storage pool first.
virsh pool-define-as --name qcow2 --type dir --target /mnt/qemu-img
virsh pool-start qcow2
 To create a Qemu guest with bridged network
sudo virt-install -n vm1 -r 1024 --disk path=/mnt/qemu-imgs/vm1.qcow2,bus=virtio,size=5,format=qcow2 -c /mnt/sda4/ubuntu-12.04.5-desktop-amd64.iso --network bridge=virbr0 --graphics vnc,listen=0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proposal Defense</title>
      <link>http://www.cs.utah.edu/~xinglin/blog/proposal-defense/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.cs.utah.edu/~xinglin/blog/proposal-defense/</guid>
      <description>I did my PhD proposal denfense yesterday and now I am one more step closer to finish it. It took a week to just prepare the talk. The talk was long and have 45 slides. However, there are only about 8 slides for each project, since there are 4 projects. The talk lasts about 45 minutes. Because it is so long, everytime I practiced it, I almost lost my voice after I finished.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clone a Single KVM/qemu Virtual Machine</title>
      <link>http://www.cs.utah.edu/~xinglin/blog/clone-a-single-kvm/qemu-virtual-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.cs.utah.edu/~xinglin/blog/clone-a-single-kvm/qemu-virtual-machine/</guid>
      <description>I am working on virtual machine cloning for security testing for the TCloud project. We are looking for an efficient and transparent virtual machine cloning technique that has minimal impact on the virtual machine to be cloned. After some investigation, we found that KVM supports live snapshot for both memory and disk state while Xen4.4 currently does not support this feature yet but could be patched to do live snapshot for memory state easily.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trade-off Between Accuracy and Runtime Overhead</title>
      <link>http://www.cs.utah.edu/~xinglin/blog/trade-off-between-accuracy-and-runtime-overhead/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.cs.utah.edu/~xinglin/blog/trade-off-between-accuracy-and-runtime-overhead/</guid>
      <description>During the weekly technical forum within the NetApp ATG group, a team member presented the trip report for OSDI &amp;lsquo;14 this year. In his talk, he mentioned a paper that pushed me to think more in this line. The paper is about how to estimate the working set of a workload, using less memory and runs much faster. The only related work that dealt with the same problem was proposed more than 10 years ago and in that work, the authors tried to get the exact working set size, with a very high demand for memory and runtime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home</title>
      <link>http://www.cs.utah.edu/~xinglin/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.cs.utah.edu/~xinglin/home/</guid>
      <description>Hey ! Welcome to the Xing Lin&amp;rsquo;s home page. Here are some articles:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>http://www.cs.utah.edu/~xinglin/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.cs.utah.edu/~xinglin/license/</guid>
      <description>You can use this page to put a license on the contents of your blog, like so:
 The MIT License (MIT)
Copyright &amp;copy; 2015 Nishanth Shanmughamnishanth.gerrard@gmail.com
Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy of this software and associated documentation files (the &amp;ldquo;Software&amp;rdquo;), to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Services</title>
      <link>http://www.cs.utah.edu/~xinglin/services/services/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.cs.utah.edu/~xinglin/services/services/</guid>
      <description> Co-chair
 IEEE Special Technical Community on Operating Systems, 2016 - 2018  Program Committees  USENIX ATC 2018 MSST 2017 MSST 2016  Journals  ACM Transactions on Storage IEEE Transactions on Computers
 IEEE Transactions on Knowledge and Data Engineering
 IEEE Internet Computing
 IEEE Computer   </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>